<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lixin Qu on Lixin Qu</title>
    <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lixin Qu on Lixin Qu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Lixin Qu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-geostrophic baroclinic instability over sloping bathymetry: buoyant flow case</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2019-ngbib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2019-ngbib/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal resolution of wind forcing required for river plume simulations</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2019-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2019-wind/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal-wave-driven mixing within submesoscale eddies</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/talk/ocng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/talk/ocng/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-inertial waves at submesoscale coherent vortices in a buoyancy-driven flow</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/talk/pecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/talk/pecs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The asymmetric continental shelf wave in response to the synoptic wind burst in a semienclosed double-shelf basin</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2018-asymmetric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2018-asymmetric/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing by wave trapping</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/niw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/niw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Texas-Louisiana shelf in the northern Gulf of Mexico is an ideal, geophysical lab to study near-inertial waves (NIWs) within submesoscale vortices. It is a broad, shallow shelf characterized by large inputs of fresh water from the Mississippi River. Submesoscale vortices within the river plume front are prevalent over the shelf in summertime, coexisting with strong NIWs generated by the land-sea breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure below shows the ray tracing within an anti-cyclone over the shelf based on a realistic numerical simulation; it suggests that the enhanced mixing in the stratified interior is highly related to the downward radiation of NIWs and the consequent wave trapping within the anti-cyclone. Wave rays converge where the interior mixing is strongest, and the wave amplification can create strong shear to trigger instabilities, turbulence, and mixing.
            &lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;trapping.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=100% /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern South China Sea Forecast System</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/project/nscsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/project/nscsf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Northern South China Sea Forecast System is a fully operational ocean circulation forecast model on the northern shelf of South China Sea based on the Regional Ocean Modeling System (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myroms.org&#34;&gt;ROMS&lt;/a&gt;). The system provides real-time analysis and 7-day forecast data for investigating coastal environments in that region. The model domain covers the entire Pearl River region and the northern shelf of South China Sea with a resolution of 1800m in the horizontal and 30 layers in the vertical. The water depth ranges from 5m to more than 3000m. The forecast simulation is initialized in 2017. The analysis and forecast fields of surface heat, momentum, and salt flux are provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/data-access/model-data/model-datasets/global-forcast-system-gfs&#34;&gt;Global Forecast System - NOAA&lt;/a&gt;. The ocean open boundary conditions are operationally created based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://marine.copernicus.eu&#34;&gt;Copernicus - Marine Environment Monitoring Service&lt;/a&gt;. The real-time river discharge data are operationally parsed from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://xxfb.hydroinfo.gov.cn/ssIndex.html&#34;&gt;National Hydrologic Information Center - China Hydrology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model has 3-hourly outputs of temperature, salinity, sea level, and currents, which are posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://barataria.tamu.edu:8080/NSCS/mapviewer&#34;&gt;Data Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northern South China Sea Hindcast</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/project/nscsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/project/nscsh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The hindcast is based on the Regional Ocean Modeling System (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myroms.org&#34;&gt;ROMS&lt;/a&gt;). The model domain covers the entire Pearl River region and the northern shelf of South China Sea with a resolution of 1800m in the horizontal (white lines in the figure above mark every 10 grid spaces) and 30 layers in the vertical. The water depth ranges from 5m to more than 3000m. The hindcast mode is initialized on January 1, 2007 and run to present, with the initial and open boundary conditions created from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://marine.copernicus.eu&#34;&gt;Copernicus - Marine environment monitoring service&lt;/a&gt;. The surface heat, momentum, and salt fluxes are provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ecmwf.int/en/research/climate-reanalysis/era-interim&#34;&gt;ERA-Interim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model is &lt;strong&gt;non-assimilative&lt;/strong&gt; to preserve original hydrodynamic features. The model performance on SST in different regions has been assessed based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mur.jpl.nasa.gov&#34;&gt;Multi-scale Ultra-high Resolution Sea Surface Temperature&lt;/a&gt; satellite data (see the figure below).
            &lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;validation.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=100% /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submesoscale baroclinic instabilities</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/ngbib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/ngbib/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coastal buoyancy-driven flows are often associated with stronger lateral density gradients than open ocean fronts, but are seldom observed to be associated with instabilities; in particular, baroclinic instabilities are seldom observed in river plumes, even though lateral buoyancy gradients within the fronts are strong. That contrasts the classical quasi-geostrophic (QG) theory of buoyancy-driven flow over a sloping bottom that predicts unconditional instability growth &amp;ndash; the QG assumption may not be reasonable in submesoscale, energetic coastal fronts. We extend the classical non-geostrophic theory to the scenario with a sloping bottom; the adapted theory predicts the suppression of instabilities and indicates that the slope Burger number is the parameter controlling the suppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure below shows the comparisons between the numerical and theoretical growth rates based on QG theory and non-geostrophic theory (numerical growth rates are calculated based on a series of non-linear numerical simulations). The non-geostrophic theory predicts more accurate growth rates than the QG theory.
            &lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;QGNG.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=100% /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the continental shelf slope around island on the Island Rule</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2014-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2014-island/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the oceanic response to winter strong wind events in the Yellow and Bohai Sea</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2014-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/publication/qu-2014-master/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
