<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on Lixin Qu</title>
    <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on Lixin Qu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Lixin Qu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://LixinQu.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing by wave trapping</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/niw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/niw/</guid>
      <description>The Texas-Louisiana shelf in the northern Gulf of Mexico is an ideal, geophysical lab to study near-inertial waves (NIWs) within submesoscale vortices. It is a broad, shallow shelf characterized by large inputs of fresh water from the Mississippi River. Submesoscale vortices within the river plume front are prevalent over the shelf in summertime, coexisting with strong NIWs generated by the land-sea breeze.
The figure below shows the ray tracing within an anti-cyclone over the shelf based on a realistic numerical simulation; it suggests that the enhanced mixing in the stratified interior is highly related to the downward radiation of NIWs and the consequent wave trapping within the anti-cyclone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submesoscale baroclinic instabilities</title>
      <link>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/ngbib/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LixinQu.github.io/research/ngbib/</guid>
      <description>Coastal buoyancy-driven flows are often associated with stronger lateral density gradients than open ocean fronts, but are seldom observed to be associated with instabilities; in particular, baroclinic instabilities are seldom observed in river plumes, even though lateral buoyancy gradients within the fronts are strong. That contrasts the classical quasi-geostrophic (QG) theory of buoyancy-driven flow over a sloping bottom that predicts unconditional instability growth &amp;ndash; the QG assumption may not be reasonable in submesoscale, energetic coastal fronts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>